<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<show>
    <meta>
        <title>The Big Bang Theory</title>
        <summary xml:lang="en">The show originally centered on five characters living in Pasadena, California: Leonard Hofstadter and Sheldon Cooper, both physicists at Caltech, who share an apartment; Penny, a waitress and aspiring actress who lives across the hall; and Leonard and Sheldon's similarly geeky and socially awkward friends and co-workers, aerospace engineer Howard Wolowitz and astrophysicist Raj Koothrappali. Over time, supporting characters were promoted to starring roles, including neuroscientist Amy Farrah Fowler, microbiologist Bernadette Rostenkowski, physicist Leslie Winkle, and comic book store owner Stuart Bloom.</summary>
        <summary xml:lang="fr">La série se focalise sur cinq personnages qui vivent à Pasadena, en Californie : Leonard Hofstadter et Sheldon Cooper, colocataires et tous deux physiciens à Caltech ; Penny, une serveuse qui vit de l’autre côté du palier et qui aspire à devenir actrice ; et les amis et collègues de Leonard et Sheldon, tout autant geeks et inadaptés à la vie en société, Howard Wolowitz, ingénieur dans l’aérospatiale, et l’astrophysicien Raj Koothrappali. Avec le temps, des personnages qui leur donnaient la réplique ont été promus aux rôles principaux, comme la neurologue Amy Farrh Fowler, la microbiologiste Bernadette Rostenkowski, la physicienne Leslie Winkle et le propriétaire d’une boutique de BD, Stuart Bloom.</summary>
    </meta>
    <cast>
        <actor ref="amy" birthday="1975-12-12">
            <firstName>Mayim</firstName>
            <lastName>Bialik</lastName>
        </actor>
        <actor ref="penny" birthday="1985-11-30" age="35">
            <firstName>Kaley</firstName>
            <lastName>Cuoco-Sweeting</lastName>
        </actor>
        <actor ref="leonard" birthday="1975-04-30">
            <firstName>Johnny</firstName>
            <lastName>Galecki</lastName>
        </actor>
        <actor ref="howard" birthday="1980-12-09">
            <firstName>Simon</firstName>
            <lastName>Helberg</lastName>
        </actor>
        <actor ref="rajesh" birthday="1981-10-06">
            <firstName>Kunal</firstName>
            <lastName>Nayyar</lastName>
        </actor>
        <actor ref="sheldon" birthday="1973-04-24">
            <firstName>Jim</firstName>
            <lastName>Parsons</lastName>
        </actor>
        <actor ref="bernadette" birthday="1980-06-23">
            <firstName>Melissa</firstName>
            <lastName>Rauch</lastName>
        </actor>
    </cast>
    <characters>
        <character id="penny">
            <firstName>Penny</firstName>
        </character>
        <character id="sheldon">
            <firstName>Sheldon</firstName>
            <lastName>Cooper</lastName>
        </character>
        <character id="amy">
            <firstName>Amy</firstName>
            <lastName>Farrah Fowler</lastName>
        </character>
        <character id="leonard">
            <firstName>Leonard</firstName>
            <lastName>Hofstadter</lastName>
        </character>
        <character id="rajesh">
            <firstName>Rajesh</firstName>
            <lastName>Koothrappali</lastName>
        </character>
        <character id="bernadette">
            <firstName>Bernadette</firstName>
            <lastName>Rostenkowski-Wolowitz</lastName>
        </character>
        <character id="howard">
            <firstName>Howard</firstName>
            <lastName>Wolowitz</lastName>
        </character>
    </characters>
</show>
